Ilyas Kussainov

★ ilyaskussainov.dev iamkussainov@gmail.com Toronto, Canada

Summary

I am a Software Engineer based in Toronto, Canada. I am the co-creator of Satellite 🗷 , an open-source, multiinstance GraphQL backend-as-a-service for dynamic web applications. I have experience with technologies across the entire stack, including JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems, and am comfortable with Docker and Kubernetes.

Skills

Backend Node.js, Express, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL,

GraphQL, RESTful APIs

Frontend JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, HTML, CSS, jQuery **Tooling** Docker, Kubernetes, Git/GitHub

Cloud Digital Ocean, Heroku

Professional Experience

09/2020 - present

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, *Satellite*

- Co-created Satellite, an open-source multi-instance GraphQL backend-as-aservice
- Built a containerized backend that generates and exposes a GraphQL API using DGraph graph database and Node.js with Express
- Enabled Satellite to support multiple backends from one deployment by using Kubernetes for container orchestration and clusterwide networking
- Configured Traefik as a reverse proxy for automatic pod discovery and SSL certificate installation
- Built an admin panel to handle backend deployment and administration using React, Express, Redis, and PostgreSQL
- Created Satellite's frontend hosting workflow using Nginx
- Collaborated with a fully remote team using GitHub and Zoom
- Co-authored Satellite's case study: https://satellite-baas.github.io/ ☑

12/2019 - 08/2020

Full-Stack Web Developer, Self Employed

- Developed open-source software using Node.js, Express, Rails, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, vanilla JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Reaction a Trello-like application built with Ruby on Rails, React/Redux, and **PostgreSQL**
- Airline Routes an interactive SVG map for viewing and filtering airline routes built with React
- Ticket Manager a ticket tracking app built with Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL

Education

2020 **Launch School**

> A rigorous, mastery-based full-stack Software Engineering curriculum that involves learning JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Networking Fundamentals. https://launchschool.com/employers 🗷

BS Mathematics, *University of Waterloo*

2016 - 2019